ALLAN JOSÉ MENDOZA JIMÉNEZ

Bachelor student in Computer Engineering looking for an opportunity as a Junior Programmer or a corresponding position. My studies have allowed me to learn from different programming tools that are needed daily and I would like to have the opportunity to show my potential and expand my experience in this area. I also have more than 10 years of experience in customer service and technical support. Strong verbal and written communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

May 2024 - Aug 2024

Junior Developer Internship

Simetría Digital

- Evaluated and analyzed solutions to address customer requirements.
- Developed and maintained APIs and web applications.
- Designed and implemented full-stack applications (Front-End and Back-End).
- Created comprehensive documentation, including API specifications, standardization guidelines, and requirements.
- Engineered database schemas and structures.
- Achieved task completion within agile sprints.

Technologies: Azure DevOPS, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, C# .Net Core, HTML, HTML5, Bootstrap, JSON, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Web Service, Dapper, GitFlow, Swagger, JavaScript, ReactJS, Entity Framework, Scrum.

Mar 2023 - Feb 2024

Spanish Interpreter

Language Line Solutions

- Responsible for listening, understanding and interpreting what is been comunicated during the conversation.
- Ability to clearly relay ideas across cultures as an integral part of the role.
- Written and verbal capacities for interpretation.

May 2021 - Sep 2022

Alexa Data Services Associate

- Responsible for the processing of data received by Amazon Alexa artificial intelligence and its derivative
- -Responsible for performing meticulous analysis of the information for the Alexa device improvement process.
- Implement workflows that allow Alexa to understand an even-greater number of questions.
- Working with my team to create process improvements or raise the quality of our output.

Nov 2020 - May 2021

Heavy Bulky Services CSA also HBS Obex Adviser / HBS PMP Adviser.

Amazon

- -Responsible for the coaching, development, and performance of new hires during the Onboarding process on HBS.
- -Call listening, mentoring sessions, metrics improvement advises, data-mining reporting directly with the CSA
- -Responsible for coaching of CSA at the bottom 10% in metrics of the organization, feedback.

Jun 2020 - Nov 2020

Heavy Bulky Services Team Captain Amazon

- -Provide information to the members of the team I have in charge.
- -Encourage the communication of peers to seek improvement in metrics.
- -Help the companions I have in charge to improve on the aspects that have difficulties.
- -Communicate information via chat or email required by the manager.

Jun 2017 - Jul 2020

Retail CSA Associate

Amazon

- -Meeting the customers needs, looking for the best solution for them like lost packages issues, contacting the carriers when needed, tracking packages.
- Experiencie in several departments like: Retail Spain US Associate, Retail Mexico Associate.

Dec 2014 - Sep 2016

Technical Support Agent (UVERSE Account) Teleperformance

Provide technical support on customer's equipments and help them through the phone to try to fix their internet connection, television and home phone following troubleshooting steps.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2024

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering Castro Carazo University

2012 - 2014

Advertising career Hispanoamericana University

2 years with no expected completion date.

2010 - 2010

Global English Academy

2003 - 2009

Liceo Académico de Puriscal

OTHER PROGRAMING SKILLS

Google Firebase DB

AngularJS

NodeJS

MongoDB

GITHUB

English Course

Bachelor of secondary education

https://github.com/mendoall

Email

ajmdza21@gmail.com

CONTACT INFORMATION

Address

Santiago de Puriscal, San Jo sé, Costa Rica

Phone

(506) 86144794

Date of birth

Feb 2, 1991

Nationality

Social links, website

linkedin.com/in/mendoall

SKILLS & TOOLS

- Quick Learing
- Visual Studio Code
- MySQL Workbench
- SQL Server MS
- Postman
- Microsoft Excel
- Scrum

LANGUAGES

native

English advanced

Costa Rican

- Leadership
- Mentoring
- Teamwork
- Visual Studio 2022

Spanish